Mss.530.1.Ar2.5
American Philosophical Society
- I. Transcripts of Oral History Recordings, with biographical information
  - Rosenfeld, Leon, 1963; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 9)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Copenhagen on: 1 July 1963 (24 pages); 19 July 1963 (19 pages); and 22 July 1963 (20 pages).
  - Rosseland, Svein, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Ruark, Arthur Edward, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Rubinowicz, Adalbert, 1963-1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 9)
    Includes 22-page transcript of interview which took place in Warsaw on 18 May 1963.
  - Rüchardt, Eduard, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Runge, Carl, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 9)
  - Russell, Henry Norris, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Rutherford, Ernest, 1946-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
    Includes extensive biographical notes, catalog of Rutherford materials at the Cavendish Library, 1946.
  - Rydberg, J. R., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Sackur, Otto, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 10)
  - Saha, Meghnad, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Saunders, Frederick A., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Sauter, Fritz, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 10)
  - Schaefer, Clemens, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Scherrer, Paul, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Schottky, Walter, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Schrödinger, Erwin, 1926-1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 10)
    Includes photocopies of letters by Schrödinger, 1926-1960.
    Also includes 19-page transcript of Frau Erwin Schrödinger interview which took place in Vienna on 5 April 1963.
    Audio of interview with Frau Schrödinger available for listening (See Mss.530.1.Ar2, Oral History Interviews).
  - Schultz, Betty, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 23-page transcript of interview which took place in Copenhagen on 17 May 1963.
  - Segrè, Emilio, 1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 25-page transcript of interview which took place at Berkeley on 18 May 1964.
  - Siegbahn, Manne, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Slater, John C., 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 10)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Cambridge, Massachusetts on: 3 October 1963 (41 pages) and 8 October 1963 (37 pages).
  - Smekal, Adolf Gustav, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Soddy, Frederick, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Sponer, Hertha [Mrs. Hertha Sponer Franck], n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Stark, Johannes, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Stern, Otto, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes transcripts of two unrecorded interviews: Berkeley, 29 May 1962 (7 pages); Zurich, 30 May 1962 (1 page).
  - Stueckelberg, E. C. G., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Stuhlman, Otto, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 7-page transcript of interview which took place in Chapel Hill, North Carolina on 8 June 1962.
  - Sugiura, Yoshikazu, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 10)
  - Szilard, Leo, 1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Tamm, I. E., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 10)
  - Taylor, Geoffrey Ingram, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 1-page transcript of unrecorded interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 9 May 1963.
  - Teller, Edward, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Thirring, Hans, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 5-page transcript of interview which took place in Vienna on 4 April 1963.
  - Thomas, Llewellyn H., 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 16-page transcript of interview which took place in New York City on 10 May 1962.
  - Thomson, George Paget, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 10)
    Includes 20-page transcript of interview which took place in Cambridge, England on 20 June 1963.
  - Thomson, Joseph John, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Tolman, Richard Chace, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Uhlenbeck, George Eugene, 1962-1963; 5.0 Item(s) 5 folders (Box 11)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in New York City on: 30-31 March 1962 (two sessions, 22 pages); 5 April 1962 (18 pages); 10 May 1962 (6 pages); and 9 December 1963 (21 pages).
  - Ullmo, Jean, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes 15-page transcript of interview which took place in Paris on 7 January 1963.
  - Unsöld, Albrecht, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Van Vleck, J. H., 1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 11)
    Includes transcripts of interviews which took place in Cambridge, Massachusetts on: 2 October 1963 (27 pages) and 4 October 1963 (31 pages).
  - Veblen, Oswald, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
    Copy of the container list of the Veblen Papers at the Library of Congress.
  - Voigt, Woldemar, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Waals, J. D. van der, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Waerden, B. L. van der, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 11)
  - Waller, Ivar, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Warburg, Emil Gabriel, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Weiss, Pierre, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes 28-page transcript of interview which took place in Copenhagen on 10 July 1963.
  - Weizsacker, Carl Friedrich von, 1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes 27-page transcript of interview which took place in Copenhagen on 9 July 1963.
  - Wentzel, Gregor, 1962-1964; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes transcripts of three unrecorded interviews which took place in Chicago, Illinois on 3 February 1964 - 5 February 1964 (18 pages).
  - Westphal, Wilhelm H., n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 11)
  - Weyl, Hermann, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Wheeler, John Archibald, 1962-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes 2-page transcript of unrecorded interview which took place at Berkeley on 24 March 1962.
  - Wick, G. C., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Wien, Wilhelm, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 11)
  - Wiener, Norbert, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1962-1964; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 11)
    Includes transcripts of interviews: New York City, 21 November 1963 (18 pages); Princeton, New Jersey, 3 December 1963 (27 pages); Princeton, New Jersey, 4 December 1963 (20 pages).
  - Wilson, Charles Thomson Rees, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Wilson, William, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Yukawa, Hideki, 1962; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 11)
    Includes 6-page transcript of interview which took place in Kyoto, Japan on 10 July 1962.
  - Zeeman, Pieter, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 11)
  - Zwicky, Fritz, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 11)
- II. Lectures
  - Copenhagen, n.d.; 24.0 p. (Box 12)
    "Faust: Eine Histoire" script.
  - Dirac, P. A. M., 1931; 134.0 p.; Dirac, P. A. M., (Paul Adrien Maurice), 1902-1984 (Box 12)
    Lectures on quantum physics by Dirac. Delivered at Princeton University, October 1931.
  - Hevesy, Georg von, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Hevesy, Georg von, 1885-1966 (Box 12)
    Audio of lectures available for listening (See Mss.530.1.Ar2, Oral History Interviews).
    Transcripts of two speeches given by Hevesy at Berkeley: "Radiation Physics in the Early Days" (10 pages) and "Madame Curie and her Associates" (11 pages).
  - Pauli, Wolfgang, n.d.; 11.0 p.; Pauli, Wolfgang, 1900-1958 (Box 12)
    "The Foundations of Quantum Theory." Lecture given before Professor Ladenburg's Seminar. Notes by M. H. L. Pryce. Submitted to the Source for History of Quantum Physics by Alfred Landé.
  - Rutherford, Ernest, 1932; 9.0 p.; Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Box 12)
    Audio of lecture available for listening (See Mss.530.1.Ar2, Oral History Interviews).
    Transcript of a lecture on nuclear physics, delivered in Göttingen, 1932.
- III. Letters
  - Bloch, Felix, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Bloch, Felix, 1905-1983 (Box 12)
    Copy of a letter written to Greogr Wentzel.
  - Bohr, Niels, 1919-1935; 15.0 Item(s) 15 letters; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters written by Bohr: 12 letters to Alfred Landé, 1919-1925; 2 letters to Dirk Coster, 1921-1935; 1 letter to David Dennison, 1927.
  - Born, Max, 1926; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters; Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Box 12)
    Copies of two letters written to Gregor Wentzel.
  - Compton, Arthur Holly, 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Compton, Arthur Holly, 1892-1962 (Box 12)
    Copy of letter written to P. A. M. Dirac.
  - Dennison, David Mathias, 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Dennison, David Mathias, 1900-1976 (Box 12)
    Copy of letter written to Mr. and Mrs. Johnson.
  - Ehrenfest, Paul, 1923-1927; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters; Ehrenfest, Paul, 1880-1933 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters written to: P. A. M. Dirac, 1926; David Dennison, 1927; J. M. Burgers, 1923.
  - Einstein, Albert, 1926-1949, n.d.; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters written to: Fritz Haber, n.d.; Pascual Jordan, 1926; William Wilson, 1949.
  - Fermi, Enrico, 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Fermi, Enrico, 1901-1954 (Box 12)
  - Fowler, R. H., 1926-1927; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters; Fowler, R. H., (Ralph Howard), 1889-1944 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters to David Dennison.
  - Gordon, Walter and Kudar, Johann, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Gordon, Walter, 1893-1939; Kudar, Johann (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to P. A. M. Dirac.
  - "Hafnium", 1923-1924, n.d.; 11.0 Item(s) 11 letters; Coster, Dirk, 1889-1950; Hevesy, Georg von, 1885-1966; Philips Electronics N.V.. (Box 12)
    A series of correspondence between Coster, Hevesy, and N. V. Philips.
  - Hartree, Douglas R., 1935-1939; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters; Hartree, Douglas R., (Douglas Rayner), 1897-1958 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters written to Robert Bruce Lindsay.
  - Jordan, Pascual, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Jordan, Pascual, 1902-1980 (Box 12)
  - Kemmer, Nicholas, 1938; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to Gregor Wentzel.
  - Klein, Oskar, 1926-1927; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters; Klein, Oskar, 1894-1977 (Box 12)
    Copies of two letters sent to David Dennison, 1926-1927; one letter sent to P. A. M. Dirac, 1927.
  - Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1927-1929; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters; Kramers, Hendrik Anthony, 1894-1952 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters sent to David Dennison.
  - Kudar, Johann, 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to unidentified recipient.
  - Pauli, Wolfgang, 1923-1958; 9.0 Item(s) 9 letters; Pauli, Wolfgang, 1900-1958 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters: 2 to Alfred Landé, 1923; 1 to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1923; 4 to Gregor Wentzel, 1926; 1 to George Gamow, 1958; excerpts of letters to Victor Frederick Weisskopf, 1957.
  - Placzek, George, 1940-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters; Placzek, G., (George), 1905-1955; Wheeler, John Archibald, 1911-2008 (Box 12)
    Copy of a telegram and money order sent by Placzek to Wheeler in 1940, settling a bet concerning the slow neutron fission of natural uranium. Also includes copy of a later letter written by Wheeler, dated 1963, explaining the earlier document.
  - Planck, Max, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Planck, Max, 1858-1947 (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to Robert Williams Wood.
  - Randall, Harrison M., 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Randall, Harrison M., (Harrison McAllister), 1870-1969 (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to David Dennison.
  - Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1920-1948, n.d.; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 12)
    Copies of letters: 1 to William Wilson, 1920; 2 to Gregor Wentzel, 1926-1928; 2 to Alfred Landé, 1948.
  - Stark, Johannes, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Stark, Johannes, 1874-1957 (Box 12)
    Copy of letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz.
  - Thomson, J. J., 1913; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter; Thomson, J. J., Sir, (Joseph John), 1856-1940 (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to Georg von Hevesy.
  - Varga, G., 1920; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (Box 12)
    Copy of letter sent to Alfred Landé.
  - Waerden, B. L. van der, 1959; 12.0 Item(s) 12 letters; Bohr, Niels Henrik David, 1885-1962; Goudsmit, Samuel Abraham, 1902-1978; Heisenberg, Werner, 1901-1976; Kronig, R., (Ralph), 1904-1995; Landé, Alfred, 1888-1975; Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988; Waerden, B. L. van der, (Bartel Leendert), 1903-1996 (Box 12)
    Correspondence between van der Waerden and Niels Bohr, Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, Werner Heisenberg, Ralph Kronig, Alfred Landé, and George Eugene Uhlenbeck.
- IV. Memoirs
  - Born, Max, 1961-1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Born, Max, 1882-1970 (Box 12)
  - Ellis, C. D., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Ellis, C. D., (Charles Drummond), 1895-1980 (Box 12)
  - Fues, Erwin Richard, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Fues, Erwin Richard, 1893-1970 (Box 12)
  - Gerlach, Walther, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Gerlach, Walther, 1889-1979 (Box 12)
  - Germer, Lester Halbert, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Germer, Lester Halbert, 1896-1971 (Box 12)
  - Hönl, Helmut, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Hönl, Helmut, 1903-1981 (Box 12)
  - Jordan, Pascual, 1948-1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Jordan, Pascual, 1902-1980 (Box 12)
  - Mott, N. F., 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Mott, N. F., Sir, (Nevill Francis), 1905-1996 (Box 12)
  - Pauli, Wolfgang, 1956; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Pauli, Wolfgang, 1900-1958 (Box 12)
  - Rabel, Gabriele, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951 (Box 12)
  - Tamamushi, Bun'ichi, 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder; Tamamushi, Bun'ichi, 1898-1982 (Box 12)
- V. Notes
  - Cockcroft, John, 1928; 1.0 Item(s); Cockcroft, John, Sir, 1897-1967 (Box 12)
  - Thomas, Llewellyn H., 1962; 26.0 p.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Box 12)
    File of notes entitled "Spinning Electron: Odds and Ends, etc."
  - Thomas, W., 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 12)
- VI. Working Papers, 4.0 Linear feet (Box 13-16)
  Papers gathered by the Archive for the History of Quantum Physics largely consisting of listings of physics courses and instructors at a variety of European academic institutions over a number of years.
  - Faculties of Universities, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
  - Universities, etc.
    - Technische Hochscule Aachen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - U. Basel, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - Bergakademie Berlin, 1.0 Item(s) (Box 13)
    - T. H. Berlin, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - U. Berlin, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - U. Bern, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - U. Bonn, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - T. H. Braunschweig, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - T. H. Breslau, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - U. Breslau, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - T. H. Brunn, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - Cambridge University, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - Bergakademie Clausthal, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - U. Czernowitz, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 13)
    - T. H. Danzig, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - T. H. Darmstadt, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - T. H. Dresden, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Erlangen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Frankfurt, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - Bergakademie Freiberg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Freiburg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Freiburg (Switzerland), 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Giessen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Göttingen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - T. H. Graz, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Graz, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Greifswald, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 14)
    - U. Halle, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Hamburg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - T. H. Hanover, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Heidelberg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Innsbruck, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Jena, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - T. H. Karlsruhe, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Kiel, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Koln, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Konigsberg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - Landwirtschaftlische Hochschule Hohenheim - Stuttgart, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Lausanne, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - U. Leipzig, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 15)
    - University of London, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - Manchester University (Victoria University), 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Marburg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - T. H. Munchen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Munchen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Munster, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - College de France (Paris) / Institut Henri Poincare (Paris), 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - University of Paris: Faculty of Sciences, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - Akademie Posen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - T. H. Prag, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Prag, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Rostock, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Strassburg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - T. H. Stuttgart, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Tubingen, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - Hochschule fur Landwirtschaft und Brauerei Weihenstephan, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - T. H. Wien, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Wien, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Wurzburg, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - T. H. Zurich, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
    - U. Zurich, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 16)
- VII. Working Papers - Correspondence (General), 3.0 Linear feet (Box 17-19)
  Administrative correspondence and records created and compiled during the life of the project.
  - Administrative Records Inventory, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 23, Box 17)
  - American Institute of Physics, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - American Physical Society, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Bohr, Niels, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Bohr Archive, Copenhagen, 1963-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Bopp, Fritz, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Born, G. V. R. (London), 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Ewald, Paul Peter, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - General Correspondence, A-Z, 1961-1965; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Goudsmit, Samuel Abraham, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Hermann, Armin, 1963-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Holton, Gerald, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 17)
  - Holton-King Project, 1961-1964; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Hund, Friedrich, 1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Joint Committee, 1961-1964; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Kahan, Theo, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Klein, Martin J., 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Kohn, Hedwig, 1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Kouznetsov, B., 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Kuhn, Thomas S., 1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
    Correspondence during travel.
  - Libraries, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - London, Mrs. Fritz, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Merzbacher, Eugen, 1962-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Miller, Alfred E., 1961-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - National Science Foundation, 1960-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Pauli, Mrs. Franca, 1963-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Pelseneer, Jean. (Related Projects), 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Project, 1960-1963; 3.0 Item(s) 3 folders (Box 18-19)
    - Preliminary Negotiations, 1960-1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
    - Proposals, 1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 18)
    - University of California Contract, 1961-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Related Projects, 1962-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Rosbaud, Paul, 1961-1963; 2.0 Item(s) 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Activities, 1961-1963; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1962; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Rosenfeld, Leon, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Sambursky, Samuel, 1963-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Sommerfeld, Ernst, 1962-1963
  - Uhlenbeck, George Eugene, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - University of California, 1961; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Van Vleck, J. H., 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Waerden, B. L. van der, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1961-1964; 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Wheeler, John Archibald, 1961-1965; 4.0 Item(s) 4 folders (Box 19)
- VIII. Working Papers - Correspondence (Physicists), 2.0 Linear feet (Box 20-21)
  Correspondence, largely of an administrative manner, between the research team and the physicists who contributed to the project.
  - Amaldi, Edoardo, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Andrade, Edward Neville da Costa, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Auger, Pierre, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Bauer, Edmond, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Beck, Guido, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Blackett, P. M. S., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Bohr, Niels, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Bohr, Fru Niels; Aage Bohr; Leon Rosenfeld, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Bragg, William Lawrence, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Breit, Gregory, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Brillouin, Leon, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Broglie, Louis de, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Burger, Herman Carel, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Burgers, J. M., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Cockcroft, John, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Compton, Arthur Holly, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Courant, Richard, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Cunningham, Ebenezer, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Darrow, Karl K., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Darwin, Charles Galton, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Debye, Peter J. W., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Delbrück, Max, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Dennison, David Mathias, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Dirac, P. A. M., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Eckart, Carl, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Ehrenfest, Paul, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Elsasser, Walter M., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Epstein, Paul S., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Estermann, Immanuel, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Ewald, Paul Peter, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Feather, Norman, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Fierz, Markus, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Fokker, A. D., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Franck, James and Hertha Sponer Franck, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Frank, Phillip, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Friedrich, Walter, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Frisch, Otto Robert, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Fues, Erwin Richard, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Gamow, George, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - George, André, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Gerlach, Walther, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Germer, Lester Halbert, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Good, Irving John, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Gordon, Walter, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Gorter, Cornelius J., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Goudsmit, Samuel Abraham, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Guth, Eugene, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Halpern, Otto, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hartree, Mrs. Douglas R., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Heisenberg, Werner, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hertz, Gustav, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Herzfeld, Karl F., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hevesy, Georg von, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hildebrand, Joel, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hönl, Helmut, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Houston, William Vermillion, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hoyt, Frank Clark, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hund, Friedrich, 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)
  - Hylleraas, Egil A., 1.0 Item(s) 1 folder (Box 20)